{
    "1": {
    "question": "What are the 3 types of rods?",
    "answer": "Concave wraps: These are used to create curls in the hair and have a dip in the middle, with larger ends."
    },
    "2": {
    "question": "What are the 3 types of wraps?",
    "answer": "Straight wraps: These wraps are used to create a uniform curl in the hair. Bender wraps: These wraps are made of foam and have a wire in the center that can be bent into different shapes to create curls. They are used to prevent tangles and fishhooks while styling. End papers, also known as wraps: These are used to prevent tangles and fishhooks in the hair while rodding. There are three types of wraps: bookend, single, and double."
    },
    "3": {
    "question": "What is the direction when rodding 45 degrees away from you?",
    "answer": "On-base technique: This involves holding the hair at a 45-degree angle away from the scalp while styling to create volume and shape."
    },
    "4": {
    "question": "What are the 3 parts of a curl?",
    "answer": "Curl, base, and stem: These are important parts of a curl and can be manipulated to create different styles."
    },
    "5": {
    "question": "What is the purpose of texturizing the hair?",
    "answer": "Removing bulk without affecting length: This can be done using a comb or other styling tool."
    },
    "6": {
    "question": "What is considered your guard when using clipper/shear over comb?",
    "answer": "Comb: This is an essential tool for styling hair and can be used to remove bulk, create partings, and guide the hair while cutting or styling."
    },
    "8": {
    "question": "What method is used with the shears to edge up around the ears?",
    "answer": "Arching technique: This involves using the comb to create an arch shape in the hair while cutting or styling to add volume and shape."
    },
    "9": {
    "question": "What is the preferred method of cutting using fingers and shears?",
    "answer": "Palm-to-palm technique: This involves holding the comb in the palm of the hand and using it to guide the hair while cutting. It is considered the most preferred technique as it allows the stylist to directly see the hair being cut and also rest the shears on their hand."
    },
    "10": {
    "question": "What is tension?",
    "answer": "The amount of pressure applied while cutting, rodding, rolling, or styling the hair: This can affect the final result of the style."
    },
    "11": {
    "question": "Why use minimum tension when cutting wet curly hair?",
    "answer": "Cutting wet hair: This will result in shorter hair when it is dry, so it is important to consider the desired final length when styling."
    },
    "12": {
    "question": "Using a straightening comb, what is a medium press?",
    "answer": "Soft press technique: This involves applying pressure to the hair to remove 60-75% of the curl."
    },
    "13": {
    "question":"What is a guide or guideline?",
    "answer": "Reference point: This is the point of reference used while cutting the hair."
    },
    "14": {
    "question": "What is the 45 degree cut called?",
    "answer": "Graduated or wedged cut: This style has a ramp-like appearance and adds volume to the hair."
    },
    "15": {
    "question": "What is the blunt cut also called?",
    "answer": "Blunt cut, also known as 0 elevation cut: This cut makes all the hairs appear to be the same length, although they are actually different lengths."
    },
    "16": {
    "question": "What is another name for the uniform cut?",
    "answer": "Uniform cut, also known as 90 degree cut: This cut creates a uniform length all around the head."
    },
    "17": {
    "question": "Which cutting angle uses a stationary guide?",
    "answer": "Long layered cut, also known as 180 degree cut: This cut is achieved by pulling the hair straight up and using a stationary guide."
    },
    "18": {
    "question": "What is diffused drying?",
    "answer": "Diffused drying: This involves drying the hair in the direction of its natural wave pattern to enhance and maintain the natural curl pattern."
    },
    "19": {
    "question": "What is over direction?",
    "answer": "Overdirecting: This involves pulling or combing the hair in an unnatural position to curl, cut, or style it. It allows for blending short and long lengths of hair at the same time while cutting."
    },
    "20": {
    "question": "What is a base section?",
    "answer": "Sectioning is the act of dividing the hair into smaller sections. Each individual section is called a base section. This can be done for various reasons, such as styling, cutting, or coloring the hair. Sectioning allows for more precise and even results when working with the hair."
    }
}

    
    